Ryan Scherr

ryanascherr@gmail.com | 410-292-1432 | Baltimore, Maryland 21228 LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/ryanascherr | GitHub: github.com/ryanascherr Portfolio: ryanascherr.github.io/portfolio/

Summary

Web developer who specializes in front-end development and draws upon almost a decade of work as a leader and team player in the field Applied behavior Analysis. Through the Coding Bootcamp at Johns Hopkins Engineering, have learned a variety of skills, languages, and frameworks, including Browser-Based Technology, API Interaction, Databases, and Server-Side Development. Passion and expertise in creating web pages with responsive design and intuitive UI, with a focus on mobile-first design and development. Looking forward to finding creative solutions to give users the best possible experience on any project.

Technical Skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, jQuery UI, Node.js, Moment.js, Bootstrap, Materialize, GIT, GitHub, APIs, JSON, Node.js, Express, Handlebars.js, PWAs, MySQL, MongoDB, Mongoose.js, React.js

Applications Built

Tech Blog | Lead Developer | https://whispering-sea-48503.herokuapp.com/

- A blog where users can post questions and reply to others' questions, with full login functionality
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, Handlebars.js, Dotenv, Bcrypt
- GitHub Repository: https://github.com/ryanascherr/tech-blog

Yoda Advice | Co-Developer | https://caitbopp.github.io/yoda-advice/

- A language translator, translating advice into Yoda Speak
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Materialize, Fun Translations API, Advice Slip JSON API
- GitHub Repository: https://github.com/caitbopp/yoda-advice

Weather Dashboard | Lead Developer | https://ryanascherr.github.io/weather-dashboard/

- Displays current weather and 5-day forecast of any city
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, iQuery, OpenWeatherMap API
- GitHub Repository: https://github.com/ryanascherr/weather-dashboard

Workday Scheduler | Lead Developer | https://ryanascherr.github.io/work-day-scheduler/

- A scheduler with time slots and fillable fields for each work hour
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, Bootstrap, Moment.js
- GitHub Repository: https://github.com/ryanascherr/work-day-scheduler

Fitness Tracker | Lead Developer | https://metric-loon-80521.herokuapp.com/

- Allows users to add exercises to a workout plan and view statistics from their recent workouts
- MongoDB, Mongoose.is
- https://github.com/ryanascherr/workout-tracker

Password Generator | Lead Developer | https://ryanascherr.github.io/password-generator/

Allows creation of a password using a series of customizable specifications

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery
- GitHub Repository: https://github.com/ryanascherr/password-generator

Experience

Behavior Analyst, August 2020 – Present

Attain ABA - Baltimore, MD

- Communicated frequently with families to discuss client progress and train on behavioral interventions
- Collaborated with and supervised Registered Behavior Technicians
- Problem solved and collaborated with co-workers to develop treatment plans for clients

Behavior Analyst I. July 2019 – March 2020

Trellis Services – Columbia, MD

- Designed data collection systems to track and evaluate client progress on treatment plan objectives
- Conducted functional behavioral assessments and wrote progress reports in a timely manner
- Developed treatment plans to address communication, feeding, behavior, ADLs, and social skills
- Supervised and gave feedback to Technicians implementing treatment plans

Clinical Specialist I, July 2018 – June 2019

Kennedy Krieger Institute, Pediatric Feeding Disorders Program – Baltimore, MD

- Relayed pertinent information to parents / supervisors daily regarding patient progress and setbacks
- Assisted in the development of individual assessments and treatment plans
- Completed evaluation reports, progress notes, and correspondence in a timely manner
- Initiated and maintained contact with KKI disciplines and outside agencies
- Provided training for parents, teachers, and/or staff

Education

Johns Hopkins Coding Boot Camp – Baltimore, MD

Certificate – Full Stack Web Development (August 2021)

Behavior Analyst Certification Board

Board Certified Behavior Analyst (May 2019)

University of Maryland, Baltimore County – Baltimore, MD

M.A. in Human Services, Applied Behavior Analysis (December 2018)

Stevenson University - Owings Mills, MD

B.S. in Psychology (May 2015)